Johnnie Regalado

\$\square\$ 250-885-7405

9 Victoria, BC

in johnnie-regalado

An independent, fast-learning, and creative web developer currently located in Victoria, BC.

I pride myself on my ability to break down coding problems into incremental tasks, learn from documentation and my own research, lead agile planning and sprints, write DRY code with effective comments, and make smart commits.

I have an innate ability to pickup new languages and frameworks and no technical challenge is out of my reach. I also bring unique experience from my past work in digital media, broadcasting and the arts.

I love building things, from big concept products to small user interactions, and I'm ready to make an impact right away.

Skills

TECHNICAL

JavaScript

HTML5

CSS3

Node.js

iOuerv React.js

Express.is

WordPress

Bootstrap

PostgreSQL

MongoDB

PHP

Creative Suite

Final Cut

Shopify

OTHER

Project Management

Video Production

Audio Recording

Graphic Design Fundraising

Ad Sales

Copywriting

Grant Writing

Experience

Pixel Union - Developer

As a developer on Pixel Union's Agency team, I am primarily responsible for working closely with our design team to create custom ecommerce themes on the Shopify platform. In addition, I manage the ongoing web services for a client with three different ecommerce sites built on WordPress, Shopify and React. I have been recognized for my strong ability to communicate project needs between clients, developers and project managers.

Benifactor / Charity Electric - Web Developer

Mar. 2018 to Sept. 2018

Sept. 2018 to Present

I developed and maintained custom WordPress sites using PHP, jQuery, Bootstrap and Advanced Custom Fields. I worked with designers and project managers to convert design files into responsive, modular web pages on time and on budget. I was also a mentor for students in the Programming and Development stream of Benifactor's Good Marketers Group apprenticeship program.

Membran Entertainment Canada - Web Developer

Jan. 2018 to Mar. 2018

As a contract developer, I was involved in the development of decentralized applications for the music industry. This involved working in Solidity to deploy smart contracts on the Ethereum network, writing server side code in Express and Node, and front-end code in React. I also contributed to the business operations through the creation of grant applications, as well as establishing version control work flows and regular code reviews.

Battlesnake 2018 - Developer

Feb. 2018 to Mar. 2018

Participated in the annual Victoria Battlesnake competition. This involved working on a small team to rapidly develop a Node, js server which worked alongside an API to provide logic for a multi-participant snake battle game. Our team were top 8 finalists in our first year of competition and also completed two additional 'bounty' challenges, one of only three teams to do so for each challenge.

oddrad.io - Technical Project Manager

Dec. 2017 to Jan. 2018

A streaming audio application built in React, Node, Express, and PostgreSQL that presents independent Canadian radio stations in a curated listening environment. I created the project concept, recruited a team of peers and set-out an agile work plan to develop a RESTful API and build a simple but unique front-end experience. As the product manager, I supported the other developers in their work through pair programming and progress reports while also tackling my own features.

CFUV 101.9 FM - Station Manager & Program Director

May 2011 to Oct. 2017

I handled all web and technical operations for the organization. I designed and deployed front-end web content for fundraising campaigns to our Wordpress CMS, maintained our organizational database through Microsoft Access, set-up and launched RSS feeds for podcasts through iTunes and Google Play, and designed graphics and posters for branding and communications goals. I also maintained the station's broadcast equipment network which included streaming audio servers, LAN and Wireless remote broadcasting equipment, and organizational file servers in accordance with University of Victoria policies.

As Station Manager (2016-2017) I oversaw all business operations of a 2290-watt FM radio station, including the management of 10 employees and 200+ volunteers. I implemented new business practices that grew our advertising sales by 140%, annual fundraising efforts by 68%, and grant revenues by 20%.

As Program Director (2011-2016) I trained, supervised and supported our staff and diverse volunteer base in the production of 126 hours of weekly radio content. I learned to have a flexible approach to training and management as I worked with students, seniors, individuals with disabilities, and marginalized communities.

Education

Lighthouse Labs

University of Victoria

Full-Stack Web Development Bootcamp 2017 An immersive web development learning program.

BFA Creative Writing & English 2011 Double major. Focus on video production and poetry.

Volunteering

Lighthouse Labs

Mentor: JavaScript Essentials Workshop

Assisted individuals, with little to no coding experience, learn web development fundamentals through the development of a chat application.

Canada Learning Code

Mentor: Getting Started with WordPress + Blogging

Supported four learners through a daylong workshop outlining how to create, use and promote a custom WordPress

National Campus & Community Radio Association President of the Board of Directors

I provided strategic direction and oversight to a national association representing over 100 community radio stations. I also communicated regularly with government officials and regulators, resulting in the successful changing of policy to reduce the reporting requirements of our members to SOCAN and the CRTC.